Quest
State University of New York at Oswego
Quest
1980 - 2015
The Quest series consists of programs, abstracts, announcements, request to participate forms, and newspaper articles.
1 linear foot.
SUNY Oswego. Center for Excellence in Learning & Teaching.
State University of New York at Oswego Penfield Library 7060 State Route 104 Oswego, New York 13126-3599
2002.008.0001
Collection is open for research.
Quest is an annual conference held at the State University of New York at Oswego, and is sponsored by the Center for Teaching and Innovation, the Office of Research and Sponsored Programs, and the Office of the Provost. Quest is a symposium dedicated to sharing the scholarly and creative pursuits of faculty, staff, and students.
1980 program excerpt: "Sponsored by the Research Committee and Office of Sponsored Research and Sponsored Programs."
1989 program excerpt: "Sponsored by the Faculty Research Committee and the Office of Research and Sponsored Programs."
2007 program excerpt: "The Scholarly and Creative Activities Committee and the Office of Research and Sponsored Programs... sponsor Quest '07."
2015 program excerpt: "In 1979 the Scholarly and Creative Activity Committee (SCAC), then known as the Faculty Research Committee (FRC), wanted to develope ways to encourage more research on campus. On suggestion was to have a Scholarly Activities at Osego Conference Day, where faculty could present their research to the campus community. FRC Chair Dr. Helen Daly organized the day, and it was decided to cal it Quest '80, in honor of the College's 'quest for knowledge.'
After the second Quest day, the following year, the administration knew that Quest would be a successful annual program, and canceled classes for the first time for Quest '82, and this practice has continued ever since."
State University College (Oswego, N.Y.); Center for Teaching and Innovation; Office of Research and Sponsored Programs; QUEST
The Quest series consists of programs, abstracts, announcements, request to participate forms, and newspaper articles.
- Programs, 1980 - 1997 (Box-folder 01-01)
  The Quest programs list: speaker, title of presentation, time, and location. Programs are included for the following years. (Number of copies in paranthesis.) 1980 (3) 1981 (1) 1982 (1) 1983 (1) 1984 (3) 1985 (1) 1986 (1) 1987 (1) 1988 (3) 1989 (2) 1990 (1) 1991 (1) 1992 (2) 1993 (1) 1994 (3) 1995 (2) 1996 (3) 1997 (3)
- Programs, 1998 - 2014 (Box-folder 01-02)
  The Quest programs list: speaker, title of presentation, time, and location. There was no program published in 2001. 1998 (1) 1999 (1) 2000 (2) 2002 (1) 2003 (2) 2004 (3) 2005 (3) 2006 (3) 2007 (2) Photocopies 2008 (1) Photocopy 2011 (1) 2012 (2) 2014 (2)
- Abstracts, 1980 - 1989 (Box-folder 01-03)
  Quest abstracts lists: presenter, title of presentation, brief synopsis, time, and location.
- Abstracts, 1990 - 1996 (Box-folder 01-04)
  Quest abstracts lists: presenter, title of presentation, brief synopsis, time, and location. 20 pages to 38 pages each. Included are the following with number of copies in paranthesis: 1990 (1) 1991 (1) 1992 (2) 1993 (2) 1994 (1) 1995 (1) 1996 (2)
- Abstracts, 1997 - 2001 (Box-folder 01-05)
  Quest abstracts lists: presenter, title of presentation, brief synopsis, time, and location. 34 to 61 pages each. Includes the following dates with the number of copies in parenthesis: 1997 (2) 1998 (1) 1999 (1) 2000 (1) 2001 (1)
- Abstracts, 2002 - 2003 (Box-folder 01=06)
  Quest abstracts 2001 was the last year that the abstracts were published in paper format. In 2002, they were available online, only. 2002- are copies made from the website. The abstracts lists: presenter, title of presentation, brief synopsis, time, and location.
- Call for Papers and Presentations, 1980 - 2005 (Box-folder 01-07)
  Quest call for Papers and Presentations and/or Request to Participate Forms for the following dates: 1980 - 1982 1985 1991 1993 - 1994 1996 - 1999 2001 2003 2005 2006 Also includes addendums for 2004 and 2005 programs.
- Correspondence + Memorandums, 1980 - 2006 (Box-folder 01-08)
  Quest correspondence and memorandums February 11, 1980 letter from Helen B. Daly, Chairperson, Faculty Research Committee, requesting Request of Participate Forms (1 copy attached) be given to those persons interested in making a presentation. February 13, 1980 letter from G. S. Schidanandan, Assistant Provost for Research & Sponsored Programs, sufficient copies of the announcement of Quest '80 (1 copy attached) for each member of your department. Immediate distribution would be appreciated. Informational sheet on Quest '80. Invitation to an informal social hour at the conclusion of Quest '80. December 4, 1980 letter from G. S. Schidanandan, Assistant Provost for Research & Sponsored Programs, announcement of Quest '81 (1 copy attached) and Request of Participate Forms (1 copy attached). April 15, 1997 letter from C. Thomas Gooding, Interm Provost, RE: Spring Honors Convocation and Quest '97, Sara Varhus, Associate Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences will be speaker and reception immediately following the ceremony in Hewitt Union. No formal classes will be in session during the day and classes scheduled to begin after 5:00 p.m. will be held as usual. Letter dated April 9, 1998, from Bill Bosch, RE: Quest '98, describing the different forms of presentations. Announcement for Quest '98. Memo from John W. Presley, Provost, Vice President for Academic Affairs to All Faculty and Staff. November 14, 2002, with reference to Quest 2003. Memos from Bill Bosch to Faculty and Professional Staff. Invitation to participate in Quest 2005 and 2006. October 2004, January 2005, April 2005, November 2005, and January 2006.
- Newspaper Articles, 1986 - 1993 (Box-folder 01-09)
  Photocopies of newspaper articles regarding Quest: The Valley News, April 15, 1986--College at Oswego's history topic at Quest 1986. The Post Standard, March 31, 1993--Oswego State to Go on 'Quest'. The Palladium Times, April 1, 1993--A successful Quest for college campus.
- Panel: Love, Sexual Desire, Happiness and Freedom in Plato, Quest 1987. (Box-folder 01-10)
  Panel: Love, Sexual Desire, Happiness and Freedom in Plato, Quest 1987. The panel consists of three papers. While all three address the concept of love in Plato and use Plato's Symposium and Phaedrus as their basic sources, each emphasizes a different aspect of this concept. Because of their common ground and difference, the three papers together give a sense of both the depth and breadth of Plato's view of love, which in many respects does not resemble the views that have currency today and is, therefore, especially interesting. Panel: Corrine Corcoran (Psych), Cathy Martin (Phil), and Pam Ryan (Phil) Sponsor: Bat-Ami Bar On, Philosophy
- Panel: Pornography, Rape, and Love, Quest 1987. (Box-folder 01-11)
  Panel: Pornography, Rape, and Love, Quest 1987. The panel consists of three papers. The paper by Ms. Ellis addresses the presentation of rape in literature and the ambiguity of its presentation. The paper by Ms. Hopkins addresses pornography and the debate about its censorship and, the paper by Ms. Maltz in contrast to the other two papers, addresses the communication of love, whether verbally or physically. Panel: Christine Ellis (Eng), Jean Hopkins (Psych), and Francine R. Maltz (Psych) Sponsor: Bat-Ami Bar On, Philosophy
- Paper: Arnold, Kim--Gay Rights Movement, Quest 1987. (Box-folder 01-12)
  Paper: Arnold, Kim--Gay Rights Movement, Quest 1987. The social movements of the 1960s and 1970s included the issues of civil rights, peace, women's liberation, and gay liberation. This paper explores the problem of discrimination in employment of gays. It was not until 1965 that the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit decided that a person could not be disqualified for government employment because of charges of gay or lesbian behavior. Testimony of C. Christensen, a dean and professor at Syracuse University Law School; J. O'Leary, President of the National Association of Business Councils; and Hon. P. Tsongas, will be examined, utilizing Rosenfield's theory of criticism. Sponsor: Joan Loveridge-Sanbonmatsu, Communication Studies
- Paper: Darling, Gary--McCarthyism: The Movement and the Meaning, Quest 1987. (Box-folder 01-13)
  Paper: Darling, Gary--McCarthyism: The Movement and the Meaning, Quest 1987. McCarthyism was based on the amplification of fears of communism, based primarily on unfounded accusations of communists being in the U.S. government. We could fall into a similar situation today. We may even deny it is happening. Finding a scapegoat and convicting a person or several people in a kangaroo court is pushing our own values aside. This paper examines the role of the media and discourse of Senator McCarthy, President Truman, and Senator John C. Stennis, using Kenneth Burke's Theory of Movements.
- Paper: Marcy, Sue--War Is Not Healthy for Children and Other Living Things, Quest 1987. (Box-folder 01-14)
  Paper: Marcy, Sue--War Is Not Healthy for Children and Other Living Things, Quest 1987. The Vietnam "conflict" was clouded by confusion. Using Marie Rossenwasser's and Molefi Asanti's Movement theories, this study agreed with Nancy Zaroullis when she said in Who Spoke Up "...the anti-war movement during the Vietnam era is important not because it stopped the war which it may or may not have done; rather it was important because it existed. It is a reminder to Americans that ... citizens can and indeed must challenge the government's authority." The anti-war protests could be seen in correspondence, speeches and songs by Martin Luther King, Jr., Bell Abzug, folk singer, Phil Ochs, and parent, Frank H. Mentz. Sponsor: Joan Loveridge-Sanbonmatsu, Communication Studies
- Paper: Mercadante, Andrea--The German Underground Resistance to Hitler, Quest 1987 (Box-folder 01-15)
  Paper: Mercadante, Andrea--The German Underground Resistance to Hitler, Quest 1987. The German underground resistance movement to Hitler demonstrated great courage. This paper will look at court testimony given by Rivka Yosselevska on May 8, 1961 from "Women in the Resistance and the Holocaust: The Voices of Eyewitnesses". Using Kenneth Burke's theory of the dramatic pentad, this discourse and others will be analyzed. The German underground resistance to Hitler and the Nazis was a widespread devoted group of people along with many others who envisioned the end of the Third Reich. Sponsor: Joan Loveridge-Sanbonmatsu, Communication Studies
- 2009 Quest Proceedings (Box-folder 01-16)
  2009 Quest Proceedings in 2 formats, DVD and printed [201 pp]. Quest Proceedings program, 32 pp.